Contact

aaron.brancotti@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/aaronbrancotti (LinkedIn) www.babeledunnit.org (Personal) www.fishbonecreek.com (Company) joinpad.net (Company)

Top Skills

Software Development Programming C++

Languages

English

Publications

Evaluation and retraining of adults' cognitive impairments: Which role for virtual reality technology?

Aaron Brancotti

Developer, Musician, Teacher, Writer Milan Area, Italy

Summary

Software Developer with focus on Games, Virtual Reality and Interaction Design fields. Broad vision and interests in philosophical, legal and artistic views of technology.

Specialties: 30+ Years Experience in Software Development; C ++, C, Java, C#, Digital Mars D, Python, javaScript, Golang; 3D, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Eye Tracking, Image recognition, Audio programming, Arduino. Unreal Engine. Will optimize non-linearly using Genetic Algorithms. Believes in Wolfram's New Kind Of Science. Technical and fiction writer. Likes teaching.

Also known as Babele Dunnit in the black depths of the Cyberspace, where he renders himself as an emerald icosahedron and acts as an Interpreter And Spokesman Between Men And Machines.

Experience

Partito Pirata Italiano
European Parliament 2019 Elections Candidate
February 2019 - Present

https://www.partito-pirata.it

Fishbonecreek
Partner, CTO and Technological Heimdallr
March 2013 - Present
Milan Area, Italy

About Heimdallr: quite difficult to describe, but something like "Technological Facilitator". Also, search who Heimdall(r) is.

ScientiaMobile Senior Software Engineer October 2015 - Present Milano, Italia Development and optimization of WURFL InFuze device detection library. C/C ++

Festina Lente

Cofounder

January 2011 - Present

...Reasoning about "the Thing after the Book"...

Joinpad

Senior Software Engineer

September 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 1 month)

Milan Area, Italy

Research, development and optimization of Augmented Reality algorithms and solutions. C++, Java/JNI/Android, C#

Codemachine Srl

Code Blesser

January 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Milan Area, Italy

Laying on of hands on code other developers write. Or, mentoring with a twist, if you prefer so. C++, Java

SR LABS - The Eye Tracking Company

Senior Software Architect

January 2005 - September 2014 (9 years 9 months)

Eye-Tracking, Handless Computing, R&D, Communication and Enabling Software, Multimodal Interfaces, Sensors and Arduino stuff

Idearium.org

Writer

2005 - September 2011 (6 years 9 months)

Writer of technical and somewhat philosophical stuff about technology, interfaces, men and machines

WideTag, Inc

Software Developer

September 2008 - March 2011 (2 years 7 months)

Mobile (iPhone) Development, Social SW, Collaborative Tagging, Ambient, Internet Of Things, Mobile Internet, OpenSpime. Co-developer of WideNoise, the Social Noise Pollution Meter.

Connect

Developer

March 2002 - December 2004 (2 years 10 months)

Third-party CTI (Computer-Telephony Integration) Development. Genesys Suite.

Dialogos 3

Consultant/Developer

2001 - 2002 (2 years)

PDA/Mobile Graphics Development (Windows CE)

First Thought

Chief Developer

1999 - 2001 (3 years)

Games/Game Engines Development

CyberFunk Italy

CTO

1994 - 1999 (6 years)

Virtual Reality development, both HW (as system integrators) and SW, primarily in entertainment field (CyberBuggy) and medical (ARCANA System).

Virtual Magazine

Writer

1993 - 1998 (6 years)

Technical writer and columnist. My "C-FIles" columns were somehow inspired by Jerry Pournelle's Byte "Chaos Manor", Douglas Coupland "MicroSerfs" and Douglas Adams' Hitchhiker's Guide.

R&C Elgra

Chief Developer

1991 - 1994 (4 years)

Virtual Reality Developer. R&C Elgra was the Italian shipper for W Industies (later Virtuality INC), the creators of VR arcade systems known as Virtuality. I developed many apps/games and demos for Italian market (offshore simulation, Pirelli tyre demo, Triennale di Milano walkthru app and more). I ported GCC C++ compiler on Virtuality systems (with the help of the IPISA Amiga User Group).

ITC Sperimentale "Villa Greppi"

Teacher

October 1983 - January 1992 (8 years 4 months)

Teacher and Lab Assistant in Electronics and Computer Science classes.

Education

Università degli Studi di Milano

Computer Science · (1983 - 1988)

ITC Sperimentale "VIIIa Greppi"

Diploma Perito Elettronico, Electronics/Computer Science · (1980 - 1983)